Cam Le Messurier

Software engineer

camlemessurier.vercel.app

camlemessurier@gmail.com

Summary

Over the past 4 years, I've had the privilege of building software for a wide array of companies, from banks to startups to consultancies. I've collaborated on a wide array of challenging projects, both big and small, and worked with some exceptional teams and fantastic people.

I have strong skills in frontend, backend, testing, and DevOps; but also in teamwork, communication, and problem-solving. I have a bias for action, am always eager to contribute, and love helping the team ship first-class software.

Relevant Experience

Software Engineer, Digizoo

October 2023 — Present Sydney (Hybrid)

I've been working primarily at ING where I'm helping build, design, and release real-time, high-volume data pipelines to power critical components within ING's current and future systems.

- Design and implementation of data streaming systems focusing on accuracy, validity, and performance at high loads.
- · Application of domain and event-driven architectural principles.
- Productionisation of the system from pipelines and infrastructure to observability and testing.

Software Engineer, Greater Bank

April 2022 — October 2023 Newcastle (Hybrid)

As part of Greater Bank's digital transformation project, I helped build and deliver a modern, cloud-first digital banking platform from scratch; new frontends, new backends, new infrastructure, and new processes.

- Helped design and implement a multi-repo release and regression strategy spanning the entire digital stack.
- Designed and deployed shared CI/CD configuration across microservices to standardise and enforce release, testing, quality, and compliance processes.
- Implemented an automated dependency management solution for 30+ repositories to meet strict security requirements.
- Performed performance testing and fixed bottlenecks, leading to considerable increases in application stability and significant reduction in response times.

Relevant Experience Continued

Software Engineer, BodyMindLife Online

October 2021 — April 2022 Newcastle (Hybrid)

Worked within startup team to build and grow new online yoga streaming platform.

- Involved in all stages of feature development from inception to deployment.
- Automated and integrated end-to-end testing via CI/CD pipelines.
- · Performed an SEO and accessibility audit and uplift.
- Responsible for an authentication microservice gateway to connect multiple IAM providers.

Junior Software Engineer, Newton Green Technologies

November 2020 — October 2021

Newcastle (Hybrid)

Worked as a full stack developer on a variety of projects for clients.

- Full stack development on communication platform for startup project in aged care
- Full stack development on well established community pest management tracker
- Front end development for various cancer research agencies

Software Engineer Intern, Userlot

February 2021 — October 2021

Newcastle (Hybrid)

As part of UON's Work Integrated Learning (WIL) project, I built an embeddable third-party widget to collect surveys from customers and capture data in a dashboard for a local tech startup.

Developer / Acoustic Technician, Global Acoustics

July 2019 — November 2020

Newcastle

Worked as a part-time developer / part-time technician. Solely responsible for delivery of a full-stack safety management tracker used by on-the-ground teams every day to log safety and compliance paperwork.

Education

Bachelor of Computer Science / Mathematics, University of Newcastle

Studied topics including artificial intelligence, systems thinking, data science, machine learning, databases, algorithms, system and network security, web development, predictive analytics, operating systems, and human-computer interaction, linear algebra, statistical inference.